[{"question": "What is the ASCII value of NULL or \\0.?", "option1": "A) 0", "option2": "B) 1", "option3": "C) 10", "option4": "D) 49", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "A character constant is enclosed by.?", "option1": "A) Left Single Quotes", "option2": "B) Right Single Quotes", "option3": "C) Double Quotes", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C String.", "option1": "A) A string is a group of characters enclosed by double quotes.", "option2": "B) If a string is defined with double quotes, NULL is automatically added at the end.", "option3": "C) Size of a string is without counting NULL character at the end", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "A C string elements are always stored in.?", "option1": "A) Random memory locations", "option2": "B) Alternate memory locations", "option3": "C) Sequential memory locations", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char var='b';\n    printf(\"%d \", sizeof(\"a\"));\n    printf(\"%d \", sizeof('b'));\n    printf(\"%d \", sizeof(10));\n    printf(\"%d \", sizeof(var));\n}\n//int size is 2 bytes\n", "option1": "A) 1 1 1 1", "option2": "B) 2 1 2 1", "option3": "C) 2 2 2 1", "option4": "D) 2 2 2 2", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[]=\"JACKIE CHAN\";\n    int i=0;\n    while(str[i] != 0)\n    {\n        printf(\"%c\",str[i]);\n        i++;\n    }\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) JJJJJJ JJJJ", "option2": "B) JACKIE CHAN", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[]=\"ANDAMAN\";\n    int i=0;\n    while(str[i] != '\\0')\n    {\n        printf(\"%c\",str[i]);\n        i++;\n    }\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) AAAAAAA", "option2": "B) ANDAMAN", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[]=\"MALDIVES\";\n    printf(\"%s \",str);\n    puts(str);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) MALDIVES", "option2": "B) MALDIVES MALDIVES", "option3": "C) M MALDIVES", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[3]=\"SUNDAY\";\n    printf(\"%s\",str);\n}", "option1": "A) SUN", "option2": "B) SUNgarbagevalues", "option3": "C) compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " Choose a correct C statement about String functions.?", "option1": "A) int n=strlen(\"abc\") returns 3.", "option2": "B) strupr(\"abc\") returns ABC", "option3": "C) strlwr(\"Abc\") returns abc", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct C statement about String functions.?", "option1": "A) strrev(\"abcD\") returns Dcba.", "option2": "B) strcmp(\"abc\", \"bcd\") returns a negative number", "option3": "C) strcmp(\"234\",\"123\") returns a positive number", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct C statement about String functions.?", "option1": "A) toupper('a') returns A", "option2": "B) tolower('D') returns d.", "option3": "C) strcmp(\"123\",\"12345\") returns a negative number", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str1[]=\"JAMES,\";\n    char str2[15]=\"BOND \";\n    strcat(str2,str1);\n    printf(\"%s\",str2);\n    printf(\"%s\",str1);\n}\n", "option1": "A) JAMES BOND,JAMES,", "option2": "B) JAMES,JAMES,", "option3": "C) BOND JAMES,JAMES,", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    printf(\"%c\",\"HUMPTY\"[2]);\n}\n", "option1": "A) U", "option2": "B) M", "option3": "C) HUMPTY", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str1[] = \"FIRST\";\n    char str2[20];\n    strcpy(str2,str1);\n    printf(\"%s %s \",str1,str2);\n    printf(\"%d\", (str1!=str2));\n    printf(\"%d\", strcmp(str1,str2));\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) FIRST FIRST 0 0", "option2": "B) FIRST FIRST 1 1", "option3": "C) FIRST FIRST 1\u00a00", "option4": "D) FIRST FIRST 0 1", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with array of pointers to strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char *code[]={\"IN\",\"USA\",\"K\"};\n    printf(\"%s\", code[1]);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) IN", "option2": "B) U", "option3": "C) USA", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with String arrays.?\nint main()\n{\n    char code[3][4]={\"IN\",\"USA\",\"K\"};\n    printf(\"%s\", code[1]);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) IN", "option2": "B) USA", "option3": "C) K", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with array of pointers to strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char *code[2];\n    code[0]= (char *)malloc(4);\n    strcpy(code[0], \"IND\");\n    printf(\"%s\", code[0]);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) I", "option2": "B) IN", "option3": "C) IND", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is actually passed to PRINTF or SCANF functions.?", "option1": "A) Value of String", "option2": "B) Address of String", "option3": "C) End address of String", "option4": "D) Integer equivalent value of String", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char *code=\"JUMPER\";\n    if(code[6]=='\\o')\n    {\n        printf(\"SUMMER\");\n    }\n    else\n    {\n        printf(\"WINTER\");\n    }\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) SUMMER", "option2": "B) WINTER", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}]
